# R. KARTHIKEYAN OC-DEPARTMENT



# **Resume Highlights:**

- ✓ Engineering (BE Aeronautical)
- ✓ Diploma (Automobile Engineering)
- ✓ NACE CIP Level-I Certified (Painting Inspector)
- ✓ ASNT-NDT Level-II Certification
- ✓ Welding Technology Training
- ✓ UAE Driving License (63598835)

# **Address for Communication:**

Door No: 9/7 M5N, S. V. Nagar,

Gudalur – 643 211, Nilgiris,

Tamil Nadu, India.

Email:keyan.ndt@gmail.com

karthi.aesa@gmail.com

Contact No:+971 566536839

:+91 7339113304

# **OBJECTIVE:**

# 5+ Years of Working Experience in Structural Steel Fabrication & Erection of Steel Infrastructure, Oil & Gas Services Provider.

• To build my career in a progressive, growth oriented organization that will produce me opportunities to develop my skills and knowledge in the field of Mechanical Engineering (Oil & Gas Sector).

#### **EDUCATIONAL SUMMARY:**

- Bachelor of Engineering (Aeronautical)
- Diploma in Automobile Engineering

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION:

- NACE CIP Level-I Certified No : (069282)
- **ASNT-NDT Level-II** Certified in (**PT,MT,UT,RT,&RTFI**)
- Welding Technology Training

# **SKILLS:**

- ✓ Good knowledge of Off-shore & on-shore painting / coating inspection (Oil & gas / petrochemical, industrial, marine)
- ✓ Welding Defect Interpretation & Rectification
- ✓ Experience and knowledge of maintaining and operating management systems to the guiding standards (ISO 9001, ISO 14001, ISM and OHSAS 18001), Auditing & Documentation.
- ✓ Strong Believer in team work & Leading a team

CV: **QA/QC Engineer** Page 1 of 3

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

Company
 Period
 Position
 Gulf Turrets LLC,UAE
 August 2014 to Oct 2016
 • QA/QC Engineer-Structural

Clients Handled: ADCO, ENOC, ADNOC, AL JABAR, TECTNIP, KENTZ, Etc...

**Responsibilities:** 

Reviewing all related documents like WPS, PQR, ITP and QAP

- ➤ Follow and Implementation of all QA/QC procedure and Quality Plans
- Responsible for stage wise welding, painting / coating inspection.
- Monitor weather condition for surface preparation and painting / coating application.
- Execute Painting / coating inspection work as per company / project inspection test plan.
- > To check and monitor all painting / coating related works and ensure all final products meet in accordance with company procedure, client requirement and international codes.
- Review all the related documents and release the fabrication Spools for packing and Loading.
- > Inspection of incoming materials and hard stamping to be checked and cross check with MTC.
- Ensure Latest fabrication drawings are available at site and being used for fabrication.
- ➤ Weld preparation (Bevel Preparation as per wps) with allowable tolerance to be ensured.
- ➤ Dimensional requirement in each stage as required and weld visual inspection
- > Document control, Control of various Inspection and measuring tools, preparation of as built.
- > Preparing of all QA/QC Documents and gets approval from client and TPI Inspector
- ➤ Assisting ISO Audit

**❖** Company : Coimbatore Industrial Radiographer, India

**Period**: August 2012 to July 2014

Position : QA/QC Junior Inspector-NDT

**Responsibilities:** 

- ➤ Document control, Control of various Inspection and measuring tools, preparation of as built.
- Review the Standard and doing the Radiography Film Interpretation and Set up the equipment
- ➤ Prepare test report for i. Accept ii. Reject iii. Rework
- ➤ Be familiar with production processes of the test material and knowledge of type and location of expected defects
- To develop RT,UT,MPT,DP technique for testing a particular job
- Prepare written instruction for Level I, Guide and check test results of Level I operators

**❖** Company : Taneja Aerospace & Aviation Ltd , India.

Period : July 2011 to July 2012
Position : Graduate Trainee-NDT

**Responsibilities:** 

- Review of Material Test Certificates, as per codes, Standard Client Specifications.
- ➤ Review and Maintaining of PT,MT,RT,UT-Instrument Calibration Certificates, Personal NDT Certificates, Batch Test Certificates for PT,MT,RT,UT consumables etc.,
- As per the client's procedures NDT inspection is done.

CV: **QA/QC Engineer** Page 2 of 3

# **PERSONAL PROFILE:**

Date of Birth, Age : 16<sup>th</sup>May 1990, 26 Years

Nationality : Indian

Marital Status : Married

Passport No. : H 8068804 (Valid up to22-Dec-2020)

UAE Driving License : 63598835

Languages Known : English, Tamil, Kannada & Malayalam (To Speak)

: English & Tamil (Read & Write)

Address (Permanent) : 9/7 M5N, S. V. Nagar, R. G. Puram, Gudalur – 643211,

Nilgiris, Tamil Nadu, India.

# **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

**Yours Sincerely** 

R. KARTHIKEYAN

CV: **QA/QC Engineer** Page 3 of 3